const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which of the following diseases requires genetic counseling?","answers":[{"option":"Angelman syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Essential galactosemia","bool":false},{"option":"Prader-Willi syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Down syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Hereditary porphyrias","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which of the following disorders is characterized by CAG repeats?","answers":[{"option":"Myotonic dystrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Fragile X syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Friedreich ataxia","bool":false},{"option":"Hungtington disease","bool":true},{"option":"Duchenne muscular dystrophy","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which of the following is the correct terminology for an amputation at the level of the ankle joint?","answers":[{"option":"Lisfranc amputation","bool":false},{"option":"Syme amputation","bool":true},{"option":"Partial foot amputation","bool":false},{"option":"Short below-knee amputation","bool":false},{"option":"Chopart amputation","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which of the following is the most common type of amputation?","answers":[{"option":"Transtibial amputation","bool":true},{"option":"Lower extremity amputation","bool":false},{"option":"Syme amputation","bool":false},{"option":"Hip disarticulation","bool":false},{"option":"Transfemoral amputation","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A 45-year-old man with transtibial amputation came to amputee clinic for a functional prosthesis. Which of these is the most commonly prescribed foot?","answers":[{"option":"Stationary ankle flexible (SARE)","bool":false},{"option":"Multiaxial foot","bool":false},{"option":"Dynamic foot","bool":false},{"option":"Solid ankle cushion heel (SACH)","bool":true},{"option":"Impulse foot","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A pregnant female come to her gynecologist and told her about the history of hemophilia in her family. She asked the doctor about the chance of presence of this disease in her child. The doctor calculated the risk and told her that it will be which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Female with 100% diseased","bool":false},{"option":"Female with 50% of carrier","bool":true},{"option":"Male or female with 50% diseased","bool":false},{"option":"Male with no disease","bool":false},{"option":"Male with 1% diseased","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Deletions or point mutations in Ehler Danlos syndrome result in reduced formation of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Fibrin","bool":false},{"option":"Dystrophin","bool":false},{"option":"Collagen","bool":true},{"option":"Factors VIII","bool":false},{"option":"Haemoglobin","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"The Malpighian layer in the skin is comprised of which layers?","answers":[{"option":"Stratum granulosum and lucidum","bool":false},{"option":"Stratum basale and spinosum","bool":true},{"option":"Stratum basale and hypodermis","bool":false},{"option":"Stratum corneum and lucidum","bool":false},{"option":"Stratum spinosum and granulosum","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Target lesions are seen in following type of drug reactions?","answers":[{"option":"Erythrema multiforme","bool":true},{"option":"Fixed drug eruptions","bool":false},{"option":"Toxic epidermal necrolysis","bool":false},{"option":"Vasculitis","bool":false},{"option":"Steven Johnson's syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which of the following theories is commonly accepted as the mechanism of action of transcutaneous electrical nerve stimulation (TENS)?","answers":[{"option":"Chemoelectric theory","bool":false},{"option":"Gate theory","bool":true},{"option":"Desensitization theory","bool":false},{"option":"Electric theory","bool":false},{"option":"Blast theory","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which one of the following is the most specific test for carpal tunnel syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Durkan test","bool":true},{"option":"Cozen's test","bool":false},{"option":"Phalen test","bool":false},{"option":"Finkelstein test","bool":false},{"option":"Allen's test","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which of the following is the most frequently asked question by parents of a child affected with cerebral palsy?","answers":[{"option":"Will my child communicate?","bool":false},{"option":"Will my child walk?","bool":true},{"option":"Will my child play?","bool":false},{"option":"Will my child ever be able to study in school?","bool":false},{"option":"Will my child talk?","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"While managing an amputee regarding stump, which of the following is the ideal shape?","answers":[{"option":"Long stump","bool":false},{"option":"Conical","bool":false},{"option":"Bulbous","bool":false},{"option":"Cylindrical","bool":true},{"option":"Short stump","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"What is the disadvantage of an upper limb prosthesis powered by an electric motor?","answers":[{"option":"Greater grip","bool":false},{"option":"More proximal function","bool":false},{"option":"Less expensive","bool":false},{"option":"Heavier weight","bool":true},{"option":"Less cosmetic","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A middle-aged female presented to her gynecologist for irregular menstruation, hirsutism, and acne. She has used so many oral as well as topical antibiotics for acne but the condition is the same. What is the best treatment in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Hormonal treatment","bool":true},{"option":"Laser therapy","bool":false},{"option":"Oral retinoids","bool":false},{"option":"Heavy dose oral broad spectrum antibiotics for a long period","bool":false},{"option":"Cautery","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A 55-year-old female presents to the hospital with shortness of breath, fever, and malaise. She has a history of breast cancer which was diagnosed 3 months ago and has been treated with chemotherapy. Her chest X-ray (CXR) shows signs of possible pneumonia and respiratory cultures are positive for Aspergillus fumigatus. Which of the following is the most appropriate choice of treatment?","answers":[{"option":"Voriconazole","bool":true},{"option":"Flucytosine","bool":false},{"option":"Fluconazole","bool":false},{"option":"Ketoconazole","bool":false},{"option":"Itraconazole","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A 65-year-old male presents to the hospital with shortness of breath and cardiac illness. Which of the following antifungal agents should be avoided in patients with evidence of ventricular dysfunction?","answers":[{"option":"Terbinafine","bool":false},{"option":"Micafungin","bool":false},{"option":"Ketoconazole","bool":false},{"option":"Posaconazole","bool":false},{"option":"Itraconazole","bool":true}]},{"id":17,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A 16-year-old boy visited the skin clinic with a complaint of gradual hair loss for 3 months. On examination, he had greasy yellow fine scales on the scalp associated with an itchy erythematous scaly rash on eyebrows, nasolabial fold, upper chest, and back. What is the clinical diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Atopic eczema","bool":false},{"option":"Allergic contact eczema","bool":false},{"option":"Discoid eczema","bool":false},{"option":"Asteatotic eczema","bool":false},{"option":"Seborrheic eczema","bool":true}]},{"id":18,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A 35-year-old female presents to the outpatient clinic complaining that she has been dropping things frequently from her hands for the past few months. This has become quite annoying for her as it is interfering with her daily activities. She also complains of decreased sensation in the middle and index fingers. What is the likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Pronator teres syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"De Quervain tenosynovitis","bool":false},{"option":"Cubital tunnel syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Peripheral neuropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Carpal tunnel syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":19,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which provocative test is used for lateral epicondylitis?","answers":[{"option":"Durkin test","bool":false},{"option":"Tinel test","bool":false},{"option":"Phalen test","bool":false},{"option":"Finkelstein test","bool":false},{"option":"Cozen test","bool":true}]},{"id":20,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A 25-year-old patient has been prescribed ultrasound therapy to control the pain due to de Quervain tenosynovitis. Which of the following is a contraindication of this therapy?","answers":[{"option":"Contractures","bool":false},{"option":"Malignancy","bool":true},{"option":"Muscle spasm","bool":false},{"option":"Frozen shoulder","bool":false},{"option":"Calcific tendonitis","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"What is the frequency of a homozygous recessive allele in the Hardy-Weinberg equilibrium?","answers":[{"option":"q²","bool":true},{"option":"p","bool":false},{"option":"q","bool":false},{"option":"p²","bool":false},{"option":"2pq","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which of the following tendons are involved in de Quervain tenosynovitis?","answers":[{"option":"Extensor carpi radialis and abductor pollicis longus","bool":false},{"option":"Flexor carpi ulnaris and abductor pollicis longus","bool":false},{"option":"Extensor pollicis and abductor pollicis brevis","bool":false},{"option":"Extensor pollicis longus and abductor pollicis longus","bool":false},{"option":"Abductor pollicis longus and extensor pollicis brevis","bool":true}]},{"id":23,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which of the following is not an X-ray finding of rheumatoid arthritis?","answers":[{"option":"Erosive arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Increased bone density","bool":true},{"option":"Bone decalcification","bool":false},{"option":"Symmetric arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Narrowing of joint spaces","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which of the following drugs triggers Stevens-Johnson syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Azithromycin","bool":false},{"option":"Warfarin","bool":false},{"option":"Sulfonamides","bool":true},{"option":"Heparin","bool":false},{"option":"Colchicine","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which disease process causes symmetrical multiple joint erosion along with multiple joint involvements?","answers":[{"option":"Pseudo-gout","bool":false},{"option":"Gout","bool":false},{"option":"Reactive arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatoid arthritis","bool":true},{"option":"Osteoarthritis","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"What is the mode of action of fluconazole?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibition of lanosterol synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of ergosterol synthesis","bool":true},{"option":"Inhibition of beta glucan synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of DNA replication","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of mitosis","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A histopathology specimen shows basaloid cells containing ducts that fit together like pieces of a jigsaw puzzle. The sample was taken from a nodular lesion on the scalp. What is the likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Basal cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Cylindroma","bool":true},{"option":"Sebaceous adenoma","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Trichoepithelioma","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Who is the best person for genetic counseling?","answers":[{"option":"Medical geneticist","bool":true},{"option":"Oncologist","bool":false},{"option":"Pediatrician","bool":false},{"option":"Specialist nurse","bool":false},{"option":"Obstetrician","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which of the following phenomena is commonly exhibited by Down syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Mitotic nondisjunction","bool":false},{"option":"Inversion","bool":false},{"option":"Isochromosome","bool":false},{"option":"Reciprocal translocation","bool":false},{"option":"Meiotic nondisjunction","bool":true}]},{"id":30,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"What is the term used to describe any restriction or lack resulting from an impairment of the ability to perform an activity in the manner or within the range considered normal for humans?","answers":[{"option":"Social participation","bool":false},{"option":"Handicap","bool":false},{"option":"Impairment","bool":false},{"option":"Activity","bool":false},{"option":"Disability","bool":true}]},{"id":31,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A 63-year-old male presents with right-sided paralysis following a stroke. What is the branch of medicine that deals with the prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of impairments and disabilities?","answers":[{"option":"Prosthesis medicine","bool":false},{"option":"Community medicine","bool":false},{"option":"Occupational medicine","bool":false},{"option":"Orthopedic medicine","bool":false},{"option":"Rehabilitation medicine","bool":true}]},{"id":32,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"During history taking and examination in physical medicine and rehabilitation, what is/are the main aspect/s focused on by a physiatrist?","answers":[{"option":"Handicap","bool":false},{"option":"Medical history","bool":false},{"option":"Range of motion and strength","bool":false},{"option":"Psychosocial history","bool":false},{"option":"Functional aspect of history and examination","bool":true}]},{"id":33,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Following a road traffic accident, a 35-year-old male's right leg is amputated below the knee at the middle of the leg. What is the most appropriate prosthesis for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Temporary prosthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Transtibial prosthesis","bool":true},{"option":"Preparatory provisional prosthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Transfemoral prosthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Definitive prosthesis","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which of the following is the least important consideration when choosing an upper limb prosthesis?","answers":[{"option":"Expected function","bool":false},{"option":"Mobility","bool":true},{"option":"Amputation level","bool":false},{"option":"Hobbies","bool":false},{"option":"Vocation of the patient","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which of the following is not a clinical feature of orthoses?","answers":[{"option":"Promote healing","bool":false},{"option":"Manage deformity","bool":false},{"option":"Protect joint","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease excessive range of motion","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in pain","bool":true}]},{"id":36,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which of the following is the most used orthosis in clinical practice?","answers":[{"option":"Cervical collar","bool":false},{"option":"Wrist-hand orthosis","bool":false},{"option":"Ankle-foot orthosis","bool":true},{"option":"Knee-ankle-foot orthosis","bool":false},{"option":"Knee orthosis","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"What is the term used to describe a change in the frequency of an existing gene variant in the population due to random chance?","answers":[{"option":"Genetic drift","bool":true},{"option":"Natural selection","bool":false},{"option":"Founder effect","bool":false},{"option":"Non-random mating","bool":false},{"option":"Gene flow","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Some types of single-gene disorders occur in individuals with a single mutated copy of the gene, and a single non-mutated allele is not enough to prevent the disease. Which pattern of inheritance best describes this disorder?","answers":[{"option":"Autosomal co-dominant","bool":false},{"option":"X-linked recessive","bool":false},{"option":"Y-linked dominant","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal recessive","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal dominant","bool":true}]},{"id":39,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which of the following procedures is a cosmetic procedure for the eyelids?","answers":[{"option":"Mullerectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Limbal peritomy","bool":false},{"option":"Frontalis suspension surgery","bool":false},{"option":"Blepharoplasty","bool":true},{"option":"Fasanella–Servat surgery","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A 17-year-old male presents in the emergency department after suffering a burn injury. On initial examination, the man appears to be breathing with difficulty and his heart rate is increased. Which of the following steps must be taken in the initial management of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Fluid resuscitation","bool":false},{"option":"Breathing","bool":false},{"option":"Circulation","bool":false},{"option":"C-spine stabilization","bool":false},{"option":"Airway","bool":true}]},{"id":41,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A 42-year-old female presents to the dermatology clinic with complaints of itching on her elbows and knees for the past two days. Her past medical record is significant for celiac disease which was diagnosed 1 year ago. On examination, grouped erythematous vesicles are appreciated on elbows and knees. Direct immunofluorescence of the skin biopsy is likely to show which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Linear deposition of the complement at the dermoepidermal junction","bool":false},{"option":"Deposits of IgG at the tip of dermal pappilae","bool":false},{"option":"Deposits of IgA at the tip of dermal papillae","bool":true},{"option":"Deposition of immunoglobulin along the plasma membrane of the keratinocyte","bool":false},{"option":"A fishnet pattern of immunoglobulin deposition along with suprabasal acantholysis","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A student is observing a skin biopsy slide in the pathology lab, he notices suprabasal acantholysis along with tomb-like deposition of the antibodies. Antibodies are directed against which of the following in this disease?","answers":[{"option":"Gliadin","bool":false},{"option":"Hemidesmosome","bool":false},{"option":"Desmoglien","bool":true},{"option":"Reticulin","bool":false},{"option":"Desmosome","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which of the following is the most common side effect of methotrexate?","answers":[{"option":"Megaloblastic anemia","bool":true},{"option":"Urticaria","bool":false},{"option":"Sideroblastic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Super infection","bool":false},{"option":"Angioedema","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A 32-year-old male presents to the emergency department after he suffered burn injuries. On initial assessment, around 30% of the total body surface area seems to have burned. Which of the following is the first step in the management of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Acticoat","bool":false},{"option":"Intravenous fluids","bool":true},{"option":"Escharotomy","bool":false},{"option":"Mafenide acetate cream","bool":false},{"option":"Silver sulfadiazine dressing","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which one of the following is the smallest unit of genetic material that can produce a phenotypic effect on mutation?","answers":[{"option":"Muton","bool":true},{"option":"Gene","bool":false},{"option":"DNA","bool":false},{"option":"Recon","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"An elderly lady presents to the clinic with a history of a long-standing ulcer on her scalp that has been growing slowly for the past 18 months. The ulcer has raised, rolled edges, and is not healing. Which of the following is most likely to be seen in the biopsy of the lesion?","answers":[{"option":"Nests of basaloid cells with peripheral palisading","bool":true},{"option":"Clusters of nevus cells in the dermis","bool":false},{"option":"Invasive groups of squamous cells with keratin pearl formation","bool":false},{"option":"Sheets of malignant melanocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Verrucous carcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A hemophilic man marries a non-hemophilic woman, homozygous for the trait. What is the possibility that their child may have hemophilia?","answers":[{"option":"75%","bool":false},{"option":"0%","bool":true},{"option":"50%","bool":false},{"option":"25%","bool":false},{"option":"100%","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"How is it possible that males with a sickness die invariably, but the trait persists in the population?","answers":[{"option":"Mutations cause this to happen","bool":false},{"option":"Moms pass it on to one-half of their daughters, who serve as carriers","bool":true},{"option":"One-half of each male and female child inherits the trait and acts as a carrier","bool":false},{"option":"Result of reduced penetrance","bool":false},{"option":"Some males have it recessively and consequently pass it on to their offsprings","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which of the following conditions is true for phenylketonuria?","answers":[{"option":"It is an autosomal trisomy associated with mongolism","bool":false},{"option":"It is an X-linked recessive trait associated with mental retardation","bool":false},{"option":"It is an autosomal recessive trait associated with mental retardation","bool":true},{"option":"It is an autosomal dominant trait associated with gynecomastia","bool":false},{"option":"It is an autosomal recessive trait associated with rudimentary ovaries in females","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A 66-year-old elderly male, known case of diabetes, presents to the clinic with the complaint of 2-3 erythematous crusted lesions on his lower shins for 1 week. The lesions have an edematous base and the crust is thickly adherent. Removal of a crust causes pain and reveals an underlying shallow ulcer. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Erysipelas","bool":false},{"option":"Carbuncle","bool":false},{"option":"Cellulitis","bool":false},{"option":"Ecthyma","bool":true},{"option":"Impetigo","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A 6-year-old school-going girl comes to the outpatient department with the complaint of intense itching of scalp for 1 month. No one else in her family has this complaint. There are a few pruritic papules present on the nape of her neck and multiple nits are noted on her hair shafts. What is the duration of time after which the treatment for her condition needs to be repeated?","answers":[{"option":"21 days","bool":false},{"option":"5 days","bool":false},{"option":"7 days","bool":true},{"option":"15 days","bool":false},{"option":"2 days","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A 30-year-old male, a known case of severe rheumatoid arthritis, presents to the clinic with the complaint of severe itching throughout the body for 2 weeks. On examination, he has large warty crusts on his hands and feet with thickening and fissuring of palms and soles. His nails are thickened and discolored. Skin biopsy shows no fungal organisms. He has been taking systemic steroids for his rheumatoid arthritis. The severity of itchiness is increasing over time. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Chronic eczema/lichenification","bool":false},{"option":"Human papillomavirus infection","bool":false},{"option":"Psoriasis","bool":false},{"option":"Norwegian scabies","bool":true},{"option":"Hypertrophic lichen planus","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A 36-year-old male presents with swollen, painful heels, and left lower back pain that wakes him up from sleep. The back pain gets better with exercise. He reports 1 to 2 hours of morning stiffness. He also has a history of psoriasis and psoriatic arthritis since he was 12 years old. It is decided to change his current regimen of indomethacin to a biologic that targets tumor necrosis factor (TNF-α). Which of the following is a chimeric monoclonal antibody that binds to TNF-α and inhibits its action?","answers":[{"option":"Sirolimus","bool":false},{"option":"Trastuzumab","bool":false},{"option":"Etanercept","bool":false},{"option":"Thalidomide","bool":false},{"option":"Infliximab","bool":true}]},{"id":54,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A 36-year-old man presents with swollen, painful heels, nail changes, and left lower back pain that wakes him up from sleep. The back pain gets better with exercise. He reports 1 to 2 hours of morning stiffness. He also has a history of psoriasis and psoriatic arthritis since he was 12 years old. It is decided to change his current regimen of indomethacin to a biologic that is a cluster of differentiation-2 (CD-2) receptor antagonist used in the treatment of psoriasis. Which of the following drugs is prescribed to him?","answers":[{"option":"Methotrexate","bool":false},{"option":"Alefacept","bool":true},{"option":"Calcitriol","bool":false},{"option":"Efalizumab","bool":false},{"option":"Prednisone","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A single recessive trait will be able to express its influence when it is present on which of the following chromosomes?","answers":[{"option":"Female X chromosome","bool":false},{"option":"Male X chromosome","bool":true},{"option":"Autosomes of any kind","bool":false},{"option":"Any of the chromosomes","bool":false},{"option":"Mitochondrial chromosome","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A pregnant woman presents to the clinic with the complaint of generalized itching, aggravated at night, for 7 days. Family history is also positive for itching. On examination, she has papules, excoriations, and burrows on her skin. What is the treatment for her condition?","answers":[{"option":"Permethrin","bool":true},{"option":"Ivermectin","bool":false},{"option":"Benzyl benzoate","bool":false},{"option":"Lindane","bool":false},{"option":"Malathion","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which of the following cells are involved in the first line of defense in the skin against any pathogen?","answers":[{"option":"Melanocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Keratinocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Langerhan cells","bool":false},{"option":"Fibroblasts","bool":false},{"option":"Eosinophils","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A family of four presents to the clinic with the complaint of increasing nocturnal itching. There are excoriation marks on their limbs and trunk. Using a magnifying glass, a few tunnel-shaped lesions can be identified in the web spaces of their fingers. What is another sign that can aid in the diagnosis of this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Tin track sign","bool":false},{"option":"Jet with contrail sign","bool":true},{"option":"Darier sign","bool":false},{"option":"Nikolsky sign","bool":false},{"option":"Auspitz sign","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A 24-hour-old baby girl, who was born at Queen Elizabeth Hospital, UK, in July 2023, went for a complete medical checkup before she was discharged from the hospital. Her blood reports were normal, but genetic testing revealed three people's genetic sequences. Her parents had had 4 miscarriages before she was born. What was the most likely reason for having three people's genetic sequences?","answers":[{"option":"Her mother was born through in-vitro fertilization (IVF)","bool":false},{"option":"The baby had mitochondrial disease because of in-vitro fertilization (IVF)","bool":false},{"option":"Her parents had a family history of hemophilia","bool":false},{"option":"Her father was born through in-vitro fertilization (IVF)","bool":false},{"option":"The baby was born by using the healthy donor mitochondrial gene","bool":true}]},{"id":60,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A 35-year-old couple visited a tertiary care hospital in Lalkurti, Rawalpindi. They were cousins by relation. Upon clinical history, the wife's hemoglobin was 7 g/dl and she had an enlarged spleen. Her gallbladder was removed a few months ago. She had had multiple abortions. She also looked pale and anemic. Upon genetic analysis, she was diagnosed with beta-thalassemia. What is the most likely reason for having this genetic abnormality?","answers":[{"option":"Nonsense mutation","bool":false},{"option":"Consanguineous marriages","bool":true},{"option":"Hyperacetylation of histone proteins","bool":false},{"option":"Defective DNA glycosylase enzyme","bool":false},{"option":"Faulty exon skipping","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"What is the karyotype of Patau syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"21 (47, XY, +21 or 47, XX, +21)","bool":false},{"option":"14 (47, XY, +14 or 47, XX, +14)","bool":false},{"option":"18 (47, XY, +18 or 47, XX, +18)","bool":false},{"option":"13 (47, XY, +13 or 47, XX, +13)","bool":true},{"option":"45 (45, X or 45, XO)","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which chromosomal abnormality occurs when a chromosome divides along the axis perpendicular to its normal axis of division?","answers":[{"option":"Pericentric inversion","bool":false},{"option":"Paracentric inversion","bool":false},{"option":"Ring chromosome","bool":false},{"option":"Isochromosome","bool":true},{"option":"Reciprocal translocation","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"According to the classification of burns, the burnt area which shows blisters filled with clear fluid and is very tender to touch falls under which category?","answers":[{"option":"Cannot be assessed on physical examination","bool":false},{"option":"Second degree","bool":true},{"option":"First degree","bool":false},{"option":"Fourth degree","bool":false},{"option":"Third degree","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A 60-year-old female comes to a primary health clinic. She complains of intense itching over her entire body, especially at night, for the last 1 week. On examination, she has a pimple-like rash on her wrists, armpits, abdomen, and buttocks. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Psoriasis","bool":false},{"option":"Allergic reaction","bool":false},{"option":"Scabies","bool":true},{"option":"Tinea corporis","bool":false},{"option":"Pimples","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A 45-year-old man has a road traffic accident and injures his right leg. He has an open fracture, with viable muscles and about a 3 cm exposed fracture site. The orthopedic surgeon plans to fix the fracture and calls the plastic surgeon for reconstruction. What is the best option to reconstruct this injury?","answers":[{"option":"Full-thickness skin graft","bool":false},{"option":"Allow secondary healing","bool":false},{"option":"Tissue expansion","bool":false},{"option":"Split-thickness skin graft","bool":false},{"option":"Fascio-cutaneous flap","bool":true}]},{"id":66,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A 26-year-old patient sustained a mixed-thickness burn, 2 hours back, involving the anterior chest, abdomen, and both thighs. The total body surface area of the burn is 25% and the weight of the patient is 50 kg. What will be his fluid requirement for the next 8 hours?","answers":[{"option":"5000 ml of crystalloid along with colloid","bool":false},{"option":"1250 in first 8 hours and adjust according to urine output","bool":false},{"option":"2500 ml of Ringer's lactate","bool":true},{"option":"2500 ml of Ringer's lactate along with replenishing insensible loss","bool":false},{"option":"5000 ml of Ringer's lactate","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"All of the statements are true regarding prosthesis, except which one of the following?","answers":[{"option":"It is an externally applied device used to modify structural and functional characteristics of neuromuscular and skeletal system","bool":true},{"option":"It is used to restore the mobility of an amputee","bool":false},{"option":"It is an artificial extension replacing missing body part","bool":false},{"option":"It is usually used to replace parts lost by injury","bool":false},{"option":"It is an artificial limb","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"An 8-year-old boy presents to the clinic with an extremely itchy rash for the past 2 days. He is the fourth student in his class to present with the same symptom. The rash is across his hands, wrists, and elbows bilaterally. Small erythematous papules with obvious burrows, looking like insect bites, aligned in 8 cm segments are seen on examination. What is the most appropriate treatment?","answers":[{"option":"Doxycycline","bool":false},{"option":"Lindane","bool":false},{"option":"Diphenhydramine","bool":false},{"option":"Topical corticosteroids","bool":false},{"option":"Permethrin","bool":true}]},{"id":69,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A 56-year-old female with diabetes presents for a routine foot evaluation with her podiatrist. The patient complains of thickening of the right big toenail and a color change (yellow). The podiatrist diagnoses the patient with onychomycosis of the toenails. Which of the following is the most appropriate choice of treatment for this infection?","answers":[{"option":"Terbinafine","bool":true},{"option":"Flucytosine","bool":false},{"option":"Griseofulvin","bool":false},{"option":"Itraconazole","bool":false},{"option":"Micafungin","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A lady sustains a flame burn to the body with 58% total body surface burn. She survives the initial ebb phase of the cycle and now requires wound coverage on her thighs, back, and scalp. What would be the best option to cover her wounds with?","answers":[{"option":"Split-thickness graft","bool":true},{"option":"Alloderm","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary healing","bool":false},{"option":"Fish skin graft","bool":false},{"option":"Local flaps","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"According to the four-color code system, what color are moribund patients assigned in case of a disaster?","answers":[{"option":"Yellow","bool":false},{"option":"Black","bool":true},{"option":"Green","bool":false},{"option":"Red","bool":false},{"option":"Grey","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"'Any loss or abnormality of anatomical, physiological, or psychological structure or function which results from abnormalities of body structure, appearance, organ, or system function.' Which of the following terms best corresponds to this definition?","answers":[{"option":"Disability","bool":false},{"option":"Handicap","bool":false},{"option":"Restriction","bool":false},{"option":"Impairment","bool":true},{"option":"Limitation","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A female athlete comes to the clinic with complaints of reduction in breast size, falling of hair, increased facial hair, and being very aggressive and anxious lately. On examination, the patient has a muscular build, signs of breast atrophy, hirsutism, and acne on the face. Which of the following drugs is she most probably abusing?","answers":[{"option":"Ephedrine","bool":false},{"option":"Amphetamines","bool":false},{"option":"Beta blockers","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium gluconate","bool":false},{"option":"Anabolic steroids","bool":true}]},{"id":74,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A 22-year-old medical student presents with the complaint of having developed a new pigmented lesion on his arm. Examination reveals a well-circumscribed, uniformly dark-brown, slightly raised lesion measuring 4 mm in diameter. A biopsy is performed and reveals groups and clusters of pigmented nevus cells at the dermo-epidermal junction and in the dermis. Which of the following nevi does he most likely have?","answers":[{"option":"Junctional","bool":false},{"option":"Spitz","bool":false},{"option":"Compound","bool":true},{"option":"Intradermal","bool":false},{"option":"Blue","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A 72-year-old female presents to the outpatient department with the complaint that she has noticed changes in one of the moles on her arm. It has become larger and the color has changed from a uniform brown to a mottled brown with blackish areas. The borders are irregular and it also itches and bleeds sometimes. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Melanoma","bool":true},{"option":"Solar keratosis","bool":false},{"option":"Dysplastic nevus","bool":false},{"option":"Seborrheic keratosis","bool":false},{"option":"Adnexal tumor","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A lady brings her 8-year-old daughter to the clinic saying that the child has developed multiple, small, rounded, hyperpigmented lesions on her nose and cheeks. The lesions get darker when she plays outside. On examination, the lesions are flat, brown, and multiple, and measure about 1-2 mm in diameter. A biopsy is performed and shows increased amounts of melanin pigment within basal keratinocytes. The density of melanocytes is normal. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Acral lentiginous melanoma","bool":false},{"option":"Blue nevus","bool":false},{"option":"Freckles","bool":true},{"option":"Lentigo","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous papilloma","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A 16-year-old hirsute girl comes to the outpatient department with the complaint of a few bumps scattered symmetrically on her lower legs that developed 1 week after shaving. Initially, the lesions were tiny but now they are slightly raised, red papules. There is no associated pain, itching, or discharge. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Tinea pedis","bool":false},{"option":"Papular urticaria","bool":false},{"option":"Furuncle","bool":false},{"option":"Contact dermatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudofolliculitis","bool":true}]},{"id":78,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A Karachi Electric line man sustained a flash burn to the neck and face and a high-voltage electric burn. He had an entry wound in his left palm and an exit from his left foot. He lost consciousness after the injury, but now his Glasgow Coma Scale (GCS) score is 14/15. He is now in emergency room, what will be the first step in the management of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Check for compartment syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Call the anesthetist for elective intubation","bool":false},{"option":"Calculate Parkland's formula","bool":false},{"option":"Start ATLS protocol and activate the trauma team","bool":true},{"option":"Assess total body surface area burn","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"What is the term for when a chromosome divides along an axis perpendicular to its normal axis of division?","answers":[{"option":"Heterochromosome","bool":false},{"option":"Isochromosome","bool":true},{"option":"Homozygous chromosome","bool":false},{"option":"Chromatid","bool":false},{"option":"Ring chromosome","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which of the following enzymes is deficient in homocystinuria?","answers":[{"option":"Homocysteine methyl transferase","bool":false},{"option":"Dihydrofolate reductase","bool":false},{"option":"Cystathionine synthase","bool":true},{"option":"Ferrochelatase","bool":false},{"option":"UDP-glucuronyl transferase","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"What is the first step in the management of the burning process?","answers":[{"option":"Stop, drop, and roll","bool":true},{"option":"Stop and roll","bool":false},{"option":"Stop, roll, and drop","bool":false},{"option":"Roll, drop, and stop","bool":false},{"option":"Drop, roll, and stop","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A 10-year-old girl with congenital melanocytic nevus on her right lower face had nevus excision and reconstruction with full-thickness graft 2 years back. Her parents bring her to the clinic with scarring and deformed lower face. Which of the following is the best plan in management of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Plan and place tissue expander","bool":false},{"option":"Re-excise and apply full-thickness graft","bool":true},{"option":"Reassure that it will settle over time","bool":false},{"option":"Physiotherapy and local massage","bool":false},{"option":"Re-excise and close it primarily","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Why burns patients are more susceptible to infection?","answers":[{"option":"No dressing of burn wound","bool":false},{"option":"Blood loss","bool":false},{"option":"Reduction in gut motility","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease in diet","bool":false},{"option":"Immunocompromised state","bool":true}]},{"id":84,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"What is the mechanism of action of methotrexate?","answers":[{"option":"Disturbs protein assembly","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of dihydrofolate reductase","bool":true},{"option":"Inhibition of dihydroorotate dehydrogenase","bool":false},{"option":"Attacks phosphodiester bonds in DNA","bool":false},{"option":"Disturbs RNA structure","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which of the following is a vitamin D analog?","answers":[{"option":"Tazarolene","bool":false},{"option":"Calcineurin","bool":false},{"option":"Caspofungin","bool":false},{"option":"Calcipotriene","bool":true},{"option":"Finasteride","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which of the following is correct regarding tennis elbow?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior dislocation of ulna is present on examination","bool":false},{"option":"It is an acute lesion which resolves within a week","bool":false},{"option":"It occurs during backhand stroke while playing tennis","bool":true},{"option":"It presents with pain and tenderness over medial epicondyle","bool":false},{"option":"It does not affect hand grip","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"In which of the following inheritance patterns, males and females are equally affected in all generations?","answers":[{"option":"Autosomal dominant","bool":true},{"option":"Autosomal recessive","bool":false},{"option":"X-linked recessive","bool":false},{"option":"Mitochondrial inheritance","bool":false},{"option":"X-linked dominant","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which of the following inheritance patterns shows male-to-female transmission only?","answers":[{"option":"Autosomal dominant","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal recessive","bool":false},{"option":"X-linked recessive","bool":false},{"option":"Mitochondrial inheritance","bool":false},{"option":"X-linked dominant","bool":true}]},{"id":89,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which of the following is an autosomal dominant disease that involves the nervous system?","answers":[{"option":"Ehler Danlos syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Familial colonic polyposis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute intermittent porphyria","bool":false},{"option":"Achondroplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberous sclerosis","bool":true}]},{"id":90,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which of the following drugs is suitable for systemic treatment of scabies?","answers":[{"option":"Albendazole","bool":false},{"option":"10% sulphur","bool":false},{"option":"Malathion","bool":false},{"option":"Ivermectin","bool":true},{"option":"25% benzyl benzoate","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A 5-year-old boy presents with generalized itching all over the body. On examination, there are excoriated papules and pustules over the genitals, fingers, and interdigital areas. What is his most appropriate treatment?","answers":[{"option":"Oral ivermectin for 7 days","bool":false},{"option":"0.5% malathion","bool":false},{"option":"25% benzyl benzoate","bool":false},{"option":"5% permethrin","bool":true},{"option":"10% sulphur","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A female presents to the outpatient department with a complaint of acne and excessive hair growth. On examination, she is obese. She has a history of menstrual abnormalities. What is her diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Acne excoriee","bool":false},{"option":"Cushing syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Sheehan syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Psoriasis","bool":false},{"option":"Polycystic ovarian syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":93,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"Which of the following is the most common site of amputation?","answers":[{"option":"At the level of hip","bool":false},{"option":"Above the knee","bool":false},{"option":"At the level of ankle","bool":false},{"option":"Below the knee","bool":true},{"option":"At the level of knee","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"What are antigen-presenting cells of the skin?","answers":[{"option":"Melanocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Langerhans cells","bool":true},{"option":"Keratinocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Merkel cells","bool":false},{"option":"Skin resident leukocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"A patient presents to the outpatient department with complaints of blisters on the skin and mucous membranes. On examination, blisters are acantholytic and Nikolsky's sign is positive. Which of the following is used as a confirmatory test?","answers":[{"option":"Skin immunofluorescence with anti-IgA antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Skin biopsy","bool":false},{"option":"Skin immunofluorescence with anti-IgG and IgA antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Skin immunofluorescence with anti-IgG antibodies","bool":true},{"option":"Skin immunofluorescence with anti-IgM antibodies","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"4th-year/drg/2023","question":"The students of the fourth year are given a form with a question about how they feel about 4th year and they can answer freely about it. What type of question it is?","answers":[{"option":"Choice question","bool":false},{"option":"Leading question","bool":false},{"option":"Open-ended question","bool":true},{"option":"Clarifying question","bool":false},{"option":"Close-ended question","bool":false}]}]
export default arr